To be continued...
That's number 10. Isn't he amazing? Seems like he always has the ball right at his feet.
Let's go!
The dumb ball went to number 10 again! That raggedy-headed kid is our only problem! We need to find a way to slow him down!
It's...
Talk about a hat-trick! We were down three golds, but we're tied now!
If we keep this up, we might actually win, which will land us a spot in the prelim semifinals.
Hard to say with how random Aoi's plays are. Watching him makes me nervous.
He's still not paying any attention to positioning our formation.
Who cares? Why do it if he doesn't have to? As long as he gets the gold.
You see? We are gonna win this thing! Yes?
Yes!
Alright! Let's go!
Hey, Ten. Your shoe's untied.
Huh?
Hey, it actually is!
Aw, crap!
Ashito, do you remember me?
Huh?
We were in club in grade school. Man, you were such a psycho ball hog then. No one ever really wanted you on their team because of it. Must have sucked knowing you weren't welcome anywhere. And you ended up quitting the club altogether, didn't you?
Right! I guess it wasn't just a dream after all. But as you can see, I'm loving playing on this team now. People change. So let's make the most of the next five minutes!
Congratulations, Derrod. Glad the Podunk Junior soccer team took you on. Feel great, Mr. Big Deal in Hicksville?
But I gotta say, the way you guys map out your plays is a snore. It's way too predictable. They pass you the ball and then go and chill over by the goal.
Least you could do is offer us a challenge.
Guess they do look like a bunch of idiots, though. All you gotta do is tell them to pass. I'm sure they think it's a great strategy every time.
You managed to get those dumb monkeys pretty well trained. Respect.
Bro! Is this a good game or what?
I'm starting to wonder if anyone told this crowd that they're watching a junior high soccer match.
Naiko, that's not nice. There aren't a whole lot of fun things to do in this town.
No way! He just head-butted him!
That dude is nuts!
You told me this was your last tournament for the school year, so I took time off work to come watch you. I am such an idiot.
Why do you go and do these kinds of things without thinking, Aoi?
Your mother came to see you play, and yet you act like it's no big deal. And then, right in front of her eyes...
What? You leave my mom out of it.
I don't suppose you're aware that Coach Kijima from Dogo Business High came out to watch the game today about getting you in on a recommendation.
He said he couldn't do it and declined. He'd heard about you and was excited about such a promising forward.
But in the end, he said he didn't need a mentally immature player.
Ehime? What the heck brought you out there?
The family grave.
Huh?
It's crazy how little things have changed. Time flows just as slowly as it always has in this place.
Well, you really ticked nose of me off. You completely ignored the team's schedule.
Someone should check the memos, because I left full details on everything.
Whatever! That is so not the point!
Are you really that freaked out? It's kinda scary.
Of course I'm freaked out!
Calm down, Hana. Now that I'm here, I'll be able to...
Get me souvenirs?
I was gonna say there's some work here I can do.
When? Now? Hey, I'm s...
We're going on two hours, you know. Even a hamster would be going insane by now.
Your legs are gonna give out.
I'm sorry, who are you?
I've been waiting for you to stop, but you keep going.
I don't blame you, that was quite a scene. I bet you're still pretty worked up.
Man, you sure are something. You were already running twice as much as the other players.
You still have the energy to come out...
I'd like to introduce you all to our newest member. This is Ashito Howie.
I call my position genius forward. I'm only interested in scoring.
I'm Ronaldo in his prime, but reincarnated. I mean, he's still alive.
But all you guys get the point. Just feed me the ball and I'll lead you to victory.
No matter where you are, just pass it to me.
I'm the reincarnation of Marco Van Basten, got it?
Except Marco Van Basten's still alive too.
All right. Listen, son.
No coach, you listen. I don't need anyone's tactics. Cause I am the tactic.
Oh, um, well, I...
I said I am the tactic. Know why I said it twice? Cause it's important!
Wow, he might be the funniest guy ever!
He's just like a goofy main character in a manga series.
We gotta throw him a welcome party.
I can't lie about who I am. I know I'm good, so I say I'm good.
If I don't wanna do something, I'll flat out say I don't wanna.
That's why I was always an outcast on every team I joined.
Until then, those guys knew who I was and accepted me right from the start.
Guess they do look like a bunch of idiots, though.
I must have fallen asleep out here. How'd that happen?
Huh?
What? Wow! What was that?
The time between hitting it with your chest and setting off was crazy!
Who the heck are you, old man?
It's just a little trick, I know.
Want me to teach it to ya?
With this up your sleeve, you could've scored, I'm guessing, three more goals today.
Wanna give it a shot?
Nope, wrong.
Don't point your midsection toward the ball.
When you receive it, that part of your body should already be pointed in the direction you want to run.
Huh.
In order to maintain your field of vision, your torso twists when you make your first touch.
And from there, you start running.
Heads up!
It's called control orientado. Come here, I'll show you.
Using only one touch, control the ball into one of these circles.
You have to be able to land it into any of them without missing, okay?
Oh, and you start here.
Once the ball's in circle, you've got three steps max to play it.
However, you won't be able to do that unless your body's facing the right way after you make your first touch.
Okay, got it.
Sorry, Ashito's not home just yet.
Right.
Where's my makeup bag?
Crap, I'm late!
Uh, really? What do you mean his teammates are out looking for him?
I'm so sorry he's causing you all this trouble.
Got it!
Oh, no, no.
They volunteered to form a search party themselves.
Unfortunately, they're coming up empty-handed.
But they're determined.
They only started winning games after Aoi joined the team.
Everyone's genuinely grateful to him.
I say just leave him out there!
Mom.
I took time away from my job to go watch him play and he thanks me with an act of violence?
I don't know if I believe all that, though.
Ashito being violent?
What reason would he have?
Shun, I'm sorry for bringing it up.
I know how tired you are from working your own job.
Oh, it's not that bad, actually.
Dinner's made. All you have to do is warm it up.
Make sure Ashito eats when he gets home!
You're so bad at this.
Know what time it is?
It's late.
Come on.
I might not make check-in time at the hotel.
Ugh.
Oh, shut up!
No one asked you to stay here all night and watch, did they?
Jeez.
Damn it!
This is so hard!
I can get the ball in the circle, but trying to hit it again within three steps is rough!
Maybe if I cut out all my extra movements?
Okay, time's up.
You've gone and tried long enough.
Close control techniques might not be your thing, and that's alright.
Guess I was expecting too much.
At this level, he probably won't make it.
But before I go,
I would like you to answer one question for me.
Okay.
There was a play you made today that I found truly spectacular.
Your team's one yen coins.
Ten yens are the opposition.
We're looking at when you scored right before you were set off.
You were here when you suddenly changed direction.
Then, you picked up the loose ball that dropped right here,
and then somehow squeezed your shot through these defenders to score.
What are you? Some kind of stalker?
You aren't really interested in tactics, are you?
All you care about is just scoring and scoring.
You run wild and hope it happens.
You can't play the game without your teammates.
Unless you want to be a jerk player.
You're a jerk player.
And yet...
Seems like no matter what, the ball comes to you.
Oh!
Damn it!
For the entire match.
Crazy.
It's like the ball's drawn to you.
It looks for the guy who plays without thinking.
That's why it seemed like you were the only one on the field.
Your teammates trust you completely and will always pass to you no matter what.
It feels natural to them.
But...
All their skill levels are pretty low.
So most of your opportunities to score came from the incredible number of loose balls you picked up.
Were you aware of any of that?
Can't you see I'm trying to concentrate?
Quit your yapping!
Wow, you're scary!
He had been acting really strange since the game ended this afternoon.
When we asked him what was wrong, he said he wanted to come here and apologize.
I'm not proud of this, but...
When we were at the game, I talked some smack about Aoi's team.
But I... I didn't mean it. I was just trying to throw him off a bit.
He seemed fine. Just took it all in and didn't react much.
I did it because he was always on the ball.
I thought we'd never win while he was on the field.
I was trying to make him hit me!
Guess your mom finally saved up enough change to buy you some real gear.
Man, remember how you used to be crazy poor?
Oh wait, I take it back.
Looking at those cleats, it's obvious nothing's changed.
Dude, it was so awkward.
Everyone was so embarrassed to play with you.
Since your mom worked the quote-unquote night shift.
If you wanna fight me, then fight me!
Call me any stupid thing you want!
I don't care, jerk!
I suck, I'm ugly, I'm a brainless idiot!
Whatever you got, throw it at me, man!
But leave my mom out of this!
Leave her out of it, do you hear me?
I'm so sorry!
We won the game!
But I felt so guilty about what happened, I didn't care!
I'm sorry!
You okay?
The last goal I made?
Well, yeah, if you only look at what was up in the area around the goal, you might be right.
But we spread all my teammates out like this for a reason.
Because they were all tired.
And because the other team's formation was neat and tight.
So I figured if I hung out in this space, I could move around however I wanted.
And worst case, I could react to any counterattack they made.
That's when I got the ball which led to me scoring.
A genius play by a genius player.
But I guess if I'm being honest, it's all thanks to my teammates who got the ball to me even though they were exhausted.
They're great!
So you see, it really wasn't a loose ball at all!
It wasn't a coincidence!
It was a team goal!
I've got a short fuse.
I can't do anything unless they let me play the way I want to on the field.
The only thing I think about is what I'm gonna do next.
And these guys, they were the first to accept me as I am.
They reminded me why I've stuck with this sport for so long.
I love playing soccer.
Anyway, that's the way it works with us.
And I like it.
Huh?
What's going on with you, old geezer?
You're starting to creep me out.
Hey, where are you going?
I need to chill for a bit.
You should go home.
Unbelievable!
Every single one of them?
That's insane.
How could that kid possibly remember the positions of all 22 players on the field?
I just fell asleep out here like some backpacker.
Huh?
There's no way. He's been at it all night.
Oh, you're up! It worked! It all started to click around dawn and I've been unstoppable! I'm even better now!
You're one creepy little kid.
I'm the manager of Tokyo City Asperion FC Youth, Tatsuya Fukuda.
Oh, okay.
Every J League team has a youth team made up of high school aged players. I have an ambition, you see. I want to have the world in the palm of my hand with a perfect team I've put together. And it won't just be a step to the stage. Our club is going to become the world.
stage. Barca, Madrid, Manchester, Milan will crush them all. And the thing that's going to make it all possible is the youth team. Come to our tryouts. They're going to be held in Tokyo.
Ten days from now. When you get home, be sure to discuss it with your family.
I knew it! That is Ashito! Hey, you have been out here practicing every day lately!
It's too bad about the tournament, but we had a good time rooting for you. We both forgot we had instruments in our hands a few times.
Yeah, but what about high school? Does that mean you missed out on that recommendation?
I'm not worried about it. I can still play soccer wherever I go.
Hi there, new team! Good job!
Yeah, thanks!
Oh! Hey! What's up, Ashito? May as well play a game with these guys since we came all the way out here, right?
Yeah! Let's do it!
Cheers!
Oh!
Hi there, new team! Good job!
Yeah, thanks.
Oh, hey! What's up, Ashito?
May as well play a game with these guys since we came all the way out here, right?
Yeah! Let's do it!
Check out Ashito.
These really got better, don't you think?
An invitation from a youth team in Tokyo.
What the heck are you babbling on about? I'm not sending you off to Tokyo alone!
How old do you think you are?
Easy.
You're still in junior high. You wanna just leave and play soccer?
Don't you know what we're going through right now?
That costs money, and we don't have much.
That sucks. I'm sorry your recommendation fell through.
So what? You're going to Fatami High then, right?
Quit the rest of us? That's so great.
Now just think, if we win, we'll set a record. Weakest team to ever go to nationals!
Yeah. Yeah, you're right. It's a good goal.
Huh? Huh. Hey, Shun.
Shun?
You've been coming home pretty late these days.
And since then I didn't have to go into work today, I thought I'd come pick you up.
Tatsuya Fukuda. He's an ex-midfielder who used to play for the national team.
That guy who gave you that invitation. He's actually a legendary player.
Really?
He's from Ehime Prefecture. From what I read. But his family moved away when he was in grade school.
He hasn't played a single game for well over ten years at least. So it's no wonder you've never heard of him.
After graduating from a big-name school known for soccer, he joined J1's Tokyo City Espirion at age 18.
Then he was promoted to starter by age 20. He hit his prime at age 23. That's when he went to play in La Liga, Spain.
You know, the best league in the world.
In Spain?!
He was a genius who bloomed early. The whole world knew who he was.
And that is where my knowledge of his history gets foggy.
From what I can remember, he suffered a serious injury in the final game of that last season.
He did make a comeback, but he never hit the same heights. He must have retired not long after.
I had no idea he became a youth team coach, though.
Ever since that day, I just... I haven't been able to get my heart to stop racing. I have no idea what that means.
Some random guy gives me pointers out of the blue, and I can't get his words out of my head no matter how hard I try.
You should go. At least try out. We'll deal with whatever happens after that as it comes. Here, take this with you.
It took me a while to save up that much. So don't waste it, okay? I'll talk to Mom. Don't worry. Something's out there for you. So go find it.
Come to our try outs. I'll take you to the world stage.
Bye.
Bye, bye, bye.
Next time on Al Ashi, Tokyo City Espirion!